John Flood, RD

Indianapolis, IN 802-309-0753

jflood215@gmail.com

http://github.com/jflood215

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-flood-developer

Objective

Dietitian turned web developer, looking to utilize an eagerness to learn and a passion for coding to transition into a Full Stack role. I have 10+ years of experience collaborating and communicating on successful teams and look to bring my drive and motivation to this new career.

Skills

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JSON, REST API's

Programming Languages: Javascript, Typescript

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Express.js

Version Control Tools: Git

Run Time Environments: Node.js

Databases: PostgreSQL Methodologies: Agile

Education

Eleven Fifty Academy

Web Development Program

Indianapolis, IN

May 2020 - Oct. 2020

24-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training.

Virginia Commonwealth University

Dietetic Internship Program

Richmond, VA

December 2008

SUNY Plattsburgh

Bachelor of Science in Nutrition

Plattsburgh, NY December 2006

Professional Experience

Noom Inc.

Remote

July 2019 – Current

- Virtual Health Coach
- Met and exceeded all expectations even as company growth exceeded 200% this year.
- Worked as a mentor to teach, train, and guide 18 coaches to be more efficient and skilled.
- Managed a high caseload consistently and efficiently from enrollment to completion.

Lincare

Indianapolis, IN

Feb. 2009 – July 2019

- Senior Medical Nutrition Specialist
 - Worked as part of the highest grossing, and most successful enteral office in the company.
 - Supported and managed multiple dietitians and offices in 6 states around the Midwest.
 - Trained over 100 new dietitian hires on all clinical and insurance related aspects of the job.

Projects

- Created a Full Stack macro/calorie calculator and recipe API using React for the front end along with Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL to build the back end. This project is currently deployed on Heroku at: https://macro-recipe-weight-client.herokuapp.com
- Created a responsive website portfolio using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap to showcase my skills to friends, family, and employers. https://jflood215.github.io
- Currently working on a group project that utilizes Git, Typescript and React legacy code with class components, along with Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL to develop a Full Stack web app for music lovers.